[{"question":" To cache your entire site for an application in Django, you add all except which of these settings?","options":[{"text":"django.middleware.common.CommonMiddleware","correct":false},{"text":"django.middleware.cache.UpdateCacheMiddleware","correct":false},{"text":"django.middleware.cache.FetchFromCacheMiddleware","correct":false},{"text":"django.middleware.cache.AcceleratedCacheMiddleware","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" In which programming language is Django written?","options":[{"text":"C++","correct":false},{"text":"Java","correct":false},{"text":"Python","correct":true},{"text":"Ruby","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" To automatically provide a value for a field, or to do validation that requires access to more than a single field, you should override the `___` method in the `___` class.","options":[{"text":"validate(); Model","correct":false},{"text":"group(); Model","correct":false},{"text":"validate(); Form","correct":false},{"text":"clean(); Field","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" A client wants their site to be able to load \"Rick & Morty\" episodes by number or by title—e.g., shows/3/3 or shows/picklerick. Which URL pattern do you recommend?","options":[{"text":"url(r'shows/<int:season>/<int:episode>/', views.episode_number)","correct":false},{"text":"path('shows/<int:season>/<int:episode>/', views.episode_number),","correct":true},{"text":"path('shows/<int:season>/<int:episode>', views.episode_number),","correct":false},{"text":"url(r'^show/(?P<season>[0-9]+)/(?P<episode>[0-9]+)/$', views.episode_number),","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" How do you determine at startup time if a piece of middleware should be used?","options":[{"text":"Raise MiddlewareNotUsed in the **init** function of your middleware.","correct":true},{"text":"Implement the not_used method in your middleware class.","correct":false},{"text":"List the middleware beneath an entry of django.middleware.IgnoredMiddleware.","correct":false},{"text":"Write code to remove the middleware from the settings in [app]/**init**.py.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" How do you turn off Django’s automatic HTML escaping for part of a web page?","options":[{"text":"Place that section between paragraph tags containing the autoescape=off switch.","correct":false},{"text":"Wrap that section between { percentage mark autoescape off percentage mark} and {percentage mark endautoescape percentage mark} tags.","correct":false},{"text":"Wrap that section between {percentage mark autoescapeoff percentage mark} and {percentage mark endautoescapeoff percentage mark} tags.","correct":false},{"text":"You don't need to do anything—autoescaping is off by default.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Which step would NOT help you troubleshoot the error \"django-admin: command not found\"?","options":[{"text":"Check that the bin folder inside your Django directory is on your system path.","correct":false},{"text":"Make sure you have activated the virtual environment you have set up containing Django.","correct":false},{"text":"Check that you have installed Django.","correct":false},{"text":"Make sure that you have created a Django project.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Every time a user is saved, their quiz_score needs to be recalculated. Where might be an ideal place to add this logic?","options":[{"text":"template","correct":false},{"text":"model","correct":true},{"text":"database","correct":false},{"text":"view","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" What is the correct way to begin a class called \"Rainbow\" in Python?","options":[{"text":"Rainbow {}","correct":false},{"text":"export Rainbow:","correct":false},{"text":"class Rainbow:","correct":true},{"text":"def Rainbow:","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You have inherited a Django project and need to get it running locally. It comes with a requirements.txt file containing all its dependencies. Which command should you use?","options":[{"text":"django-admin startproject requirements.txt","correct":false},{"text":"python install -r requirements.txt","correct":false},{"text":"pip install -r requirements.txt","correct":true},{"text":"pip install Django","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which best practice is NOT relevant to migrations?","options":[{"text":"To make sure that your migrations are up to date, you should run updatemigrations before running your tests.","correct":true},{"text":"You should back up your production database before running a migration.","correct":false},{"text":"Your migration code should be under source control.","correct":false},{"text":"If a project has a lot of data, you should test against a staging copy before running the migration on production.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What will this URL pattern match? url(r'^\\$', views.hello)","options":[{"text":"a string beginning with the letter Ra string beginning with the letter R","correct":false},{"text":"an empty string at the server root","correct":true},{"text":"a string containing ^ and $a string containing ^ and $","correct":false},{"text":"an empty string anywhere in the URLan empty string anywhere in the URL","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the typical order of an HTTP request/response cycle in Django?","options":[{"text":"URL > view > template","correct":true},{"text":"form > model > view","correct":false},{"text":"template > view > model","correct":false},{"text":"URL > template > view > model","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Django's class-based generic views provide which classes that implement common web development tasks?","options":[{"text":"concrete","correct":false},{"text":"thread-safe","correct":false},{"text":"abstract","correct":true},{"text":"dynamic","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which skills do you need to maintain a set of Django templates?","options":[{"text":"template syntax","correct":false},{"text":"HTML and template syntax","correct":true},{"text":"Python, HTML, and template syntax","correct":false},{"text":"Python and template syntax","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". How would you define the relationship between a star and a constellation in a Django model?","options":[{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nclass Star(models.Model):\nconstellation = models.ManyToManyField(Constellation)\nclass Constellation(models.Model):\nname = models.CharField(max_length=100)\n```"},{"question":". Which is NOT a valid step in configuring your Django 2.x instance to serve up static files such as images or CSS?","options":[{"text":"In your urls file, add a pattern that includes the name of your static directory.","correct":true},{"text":"Create a directory named static inside your app directory.","correct":false},{"text":"Create a directory named after the app under the static directory, and place static files inside.","correct":false},{"text":"Use the template tag {percentage mark load static percentage mark}.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the correct way to make a variable available to all of your templates?","options":[{"text":"Set a session variable.","correct":false},{"text":"Use a global variable.","correct":false},{"text":"Add a dictionary to the template context.","correct":false},{"text":"Use RequestContext.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Should you create a custom user model for new projects?","options":[{"text":"No. Using a custom user model could break the admin interface and some third-party apps.","correct":false},{"text":"Yes. It is easier to make changes once it goes into production.","correct":false},{"text":"No. Django's built-in models.User class has been tried and tested—no point in reinventing the wheel.","correct":true},{"text":"Yes, as there is no other option.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You want to create a page that allows editing of two classes connected by a foreign key (e.g., a question and answer that reside in separate tables). What Django feature can you use?","options":[{"text":"actions","correct":true},{"text":"admin","correct":false},{"text":"mezcal","correct":false},{"text":"inlines","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Why are QuerySets considered \"lazy\"?","options":[{"text":"The results of a QuerySet are not ordered.","correct":false},{"text":"QuerySets do not create any database activity until they are evaluated.","correct":true},{"text":"QuerySets do not load objects into memory until they are needed.","correct":false},{"text":"Using QuerySets, you cannot execute more complex queries.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You receive a `MultiValueDictKeyError` when trying to access a request parameter with the following code: request.GET['search_term']. Which solution will NOT help you in this scenario?","options":[{"text":"Switch to using POST instead of GET as the request method.","correct":true},{"text":"Make sure the input field in your form is also named \"search_term\".","correct":false},{"text":"Use MultiValueDict's GET method instead of hitting the dictionary directly like this: request.GET.get('search_term', '').","correct":false},{"text":"Check if the search_term parameter is present in the request before attempting to access it.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which function of Django's Form class will render a form's fields as a series of <p> tags?","options":[{"text":"show_fields()","correct":false},{"text":"as_p()","correct":true},{"text":"as_table()","correct":false},{"text":"fields()","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You have found a bug in Django and you want to submit a patch. Which is the correct procedure?","options":[{"text":"Fork the Django repository GitHub.","correct":false},{"text":"Submit a pull request.","correct":false},{"text":"all of these answers.","correct":true},{"text":"Run Django's test suite.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Django supplies sensible default values for settings. In which Python module can you find these settings?","options":[{"text":"django.utils.default_settings.py","correct":false},{"text":"django.utils.global_settings.py","correct":false},{"text":"django.conf.default_settings.py","correct":false},{"text":"django.conf.global_settings.py","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which variable name is best according to PEP 8 guidelines?","options":[{"text":"numFingers","correct":false},{"text":"number-of-Fingers","correct":false},{"text":"number_of_fingers","correct":true},{"text":"finger_num","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". A project has accumulated 500 migrations. Which course of action would you pursue?","options":[{"text":"Manually merge your migration files to reduce the number","correct":false},{"text":"Don't worry about the number","correct":false},{"text":"Try to minimize the number of migrations","correct":false},{"text":"Use squashmigrations to reduce the number","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What does an F() object allow you when dealing with models?","options":[{"text":"perform db operations without fetching a model object","correct":true},{"text":"define db transaction isolation levels","correct":false},{"text":"use aggregate functions more easily","correct":false},{"text":"build reusable QuerySets","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which is not a django filed type for integers?","options":[{"text":"SmallIntegerField","correct":false},{"text":"NegativeIntegerField","correct":true},{"text":"BigAutoField","correct":false},{"text":"PositiveIntegerField","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which will show the currently installed version?","options":[{"text":"print (django.version)","correct":false},{"text":"import django django.getVersion()","correct":false},{"text":"import django django.get_version()","correct":true},{"text":"python -c django --version","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You should use the http method ** to read data and ** to update or create data","options":[{"text":"read;write","correct":false},{"text":"get; post","correct":false},{"text":"post; get","correct":false},{"text":"get; patch","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". When should you employ the POST method over GET for submitting data?","options":[{"text":"when efficiency is important","correct":false},{"text":"for caching data","correct":false},{"text":"help your browser with debugging","correct":false},{"text":"data may be sensitive","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". When to use the Django sites framework?","options":[{"text":"if your single installation powers more than one site","correct":true},{"text":"if you need to serve static as well as dynamic content","correct":false},{"text":"if you want your app have a fully qualified domain name","correct":false},{"text":"if you are expecting more than 10.000 users","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which infrastructure do you need:","options":[{"text":"inizialized array called validators","correct":false},{"text":"a validators file containing a function called validate_spelling imported at the top of model","correct":true},{"text":"a validators file containing a function called validate imported at the top of model","correct":false},{"text":"spelling package imported at the top of model","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What decorator is used to require that a view accepts only the get and head methods?","options":[{"text":"require_safe()","correct":true},{"text":"require_put()","correct":false},{"text":"require_post()","correct":false},{"text":"require_get()","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". How would you define the relation between a book and an author - book has only one author.","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nclass Author (models.model):\nname=models.charfield(max_length=100)\nclass Book(models.model):\nauthor=Author.name\n```"},{"question":". What is a callable that takes a value and raises an error if the value fails?","options":[{"text":"validator","correct":true},{"text":"deodorizer","correct":false},{"text":"mediator","correct":false},{"text":"regular expression","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". To secure an API endpoint, making it accessible to registered users only, you can replace the rest_framework.permissions.allowAny value in the default_permissions section of your settings.py to","options":[{"text":"rest_framework.permissions.IsAdminUser","correct":false},{"text":"rest_framework.permissions.IsAuthenticated","correct":true},{"text":"rest_framework.permissions.IsAuthorized","correct":false},{"text":"rest_framework.permissions.IsRegistered","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which command would you use to apply a migration?","options":[{"text":"makemigration","correct":false},{"text":"update_db","correct":false},{"text":"applymigration","correct":false},{"text":"migrate","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which type of class allows QuerySets and model instances to be converted to native Python data types for use in APIs?","options":[{"text":"objectwriters","correct":false},{"text":"serializers","correct":true},{"text":"picklers","correct":false},{"text":"viewsets","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". How should the code end?","options":[{"text":"{ percentage else percentage}","correct":false},{"text":"{percentage endif percentage}","correct":true},{"text":"Nothing needed","correct":false},{"text":"{percentage end percentage}","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\n{ percentage if spark >= 50 percentage }\nLots of spark\n{percentage elif spark == 42 percentage}\n```"},{"question":" Which code block will create a serializer?","options":[{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nfrom django.db import serializers\nfrom .models import Planet\nclass PlanetSerializer(serializers.ModelSerializer):\nclass Meta:\nfields=('name')\nmodel=Planet\n```"},{"question":" Which class allows you to automatically create a Serializer class with fields and validators that correspond to your model's fields?","options":[{"text":"ModelSerializer","correct":true},{"text":"Model","correct":false},{"text":"DataSerializer","correct":false},{"text":"ModelToSerializer","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Which command to access the built-in admin tool for the first time?","options":[{"text":"django-admin setup","correct":false},{"text":"django-admin runserver","correct":false},{"text":"python manage.py createuser","correct":false},{"text":"python manage.py createsuperuser","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Virtual environments are for managing dependencies. Which granularity works best?","options":[{"text":"you should set up a new virtualenv for each Django project","correct":true},{"text":"They should not be used","correct":false},{"text":"Use the same venv for all your Django work","correct":false},{"text":"Use a new venv for each Django app","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What executes various Django commands such as running a webserver or creating an app?","options":[{"text":"migrate.py","correct":false},{"text":"wsgi.py","correct":false},{"text":"manage.py","correct":true},{"text":"runserver","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What do Django best practice suggest should be \"fat\"?","options":[{"text":"models","correct":true},{"text":"controllers","correct":false},{"text":"programmers","correct":false},{"text":"clients","correct":false}],"illustrator":""}]